M. L. Parrish Collection of Victorian Novelists, 1806-1958 (bulk 1830s-1930s ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Special Collections.
- Series 2: Author Files, 1734-1975; 35 boxes (34 partial)
  - Lytton, Edward Robert Bulwer-Lytton, 1st Earl of, 1831-1891; 13 folders
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (1 of 3), undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Letters to American Publishers, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Letter to General Bulwer, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Letter to Sir Philip, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Letters to Helen Taylor, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Letter to J. H. Ingram, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (2 of 3), undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with Frederic Chapman, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Letters to "My Dear Friend", undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (3 of 3), undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Lytton, Rosina Doyle Wheeler Bulwer-, Baroness, 1802-1882; 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - MacMillan, Alexander, 1818-1896; 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - MacMillan & Co., undated; 1 folder
    - Alice's Adventures in Wonderland (photostat of page in ledger), undated; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Madan, Falconer, 1851-1935; 8 folders (8 partial)
    - Correspondence and other items concerning the Lewis Carroll Centenary Exhibition in London, 1932; portion of 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Morris L. Parrish, 1924-1926; portion of 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Morris L. Parrish, 1927-1929; portion of 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Morris L. Parrish, 1930-1934; portion of 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Letters to Madan from C. H. W. Dodgson and others; notes and clippings, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, notes, etc., concerning C. L. Dodgson (Lewis Carroll), undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Supplements to the Dodgson Handbook, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Material concerning the Dodgson family, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Martins, Albinus, undated; portion of 1 folder
    - ALS to H. F. Chorley, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Maxwell, Mary Elizabeth Braddon, 1837-1915; portions of 2 boxes
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Letters to Lady Monckton (1 of 2), undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Letters to Lady Monckton (2 of 2), undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Letters to Lady Anna Chandos Pole, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Lady Audley's Secret, copyright registration, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Meredith, George, 1828-1909; 3 folders (3 partial)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Accounts with MacMillan & Co., undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Meredith, William Maxse, undated; portion of 1 folder
    - 1 ALS to Miss Clementina Black, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Millais, Sir John Everett, Bart, 1829-1896; portion of 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Mitchell, John Kearsley, 1871, undated; 1 folder
    [Note: 2 other poems to Parrish are in Box 104]
    - "To Morrie" (poem addressed to Parrish), undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Oliphant, Laurence, 1829-1888; 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Osbourne, Lloyd, 1868-1947; 3 folders
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Letters to Maurice Colles and others, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Agreement with Godfrey Hamilton authorizing dramatization of R. L. Stevenson's Prince Otto, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Paget, Augustus Berkeley, Sir, 1823-1896; 1 folder
    - 1 ALS to Mrs. [Maria Ternan] Taylor, with a message for Mr. [Thomas Adolphus] Trollope, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Parrish, George Dillwyn, 1820-1871; 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Paton, Sir Joseph Noel, 1821-1901; 1 folder
    - "Actaeon in Hades," with three other items, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Payn, James, 1830-1898; 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Powers, Hiram, 1805-1873; 1 folder
    - ALS to Nicholas Longworth and miscellaneous papers, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Proctor, Adelaide Anne, 1825-1864; portion of 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Quiller-Couch, Sir Arthur Thomas and Mabel, 1825-1864; portion of 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Papers and Correspondence, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 21A)
  - de la Ramée, Marie Louise, undated; 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 21B)
  - Reade, Cecilia Jane, 1847, undated; portion of 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Reade, Charles, 1814-1884; 2 folders (2 partial)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (1 of 3), 110 letters, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (2 of 3), 68 letters, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Reade, Charles, 1814-1884; 23 folders (8 partial)
    [Note: For more of Reade's Real Estate Papers, ]
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (3 of 3), 107 letters, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Letters to Cassell and Company, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Letters to Wilkie Collins, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Letters to M. de Wailly, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Letters to Hunter, Rose & Co., dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Letters to Laurie and Keen, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Letters to Frederick and Nina Lehmann, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Letters to Tom Taylor, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Letters to Anthony Trollope and Son (Henry), undated; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Letters to Benjamin Webster, undated; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Letters to Emile Zola, including 5 photographs of Weybridge, undated; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Letters addressed to Reade, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - "Specification and Estimate for Sicilian Marble Tomb... for C. Reade, Esq.", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Reade vs. Seaman: material relating to the libel proceedings (1 of 3; 2 of 3 folder is in oversize box 3B), undated; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Reade vs. Seaman: material relating to the libel proceedings (3 of 3), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Real Estate Papers: 6 Bolton Road, 1862-1883; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Real Estate Papers: 15 Half Moon Street, 1866-1868; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Real Estate Papers: 5 Albert Terrace, 1866-1873; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Real Estate Papers: Brompton Road and other properties, 1866-1874; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Insurance Papers, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - Reade vs. Pawle, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - Reade vs. Thorpe, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Reade, Charles, 1814-1884; 21 folders (13 partial)
    - Papers written after Reade's death, relating to real estate, etc. (1 of 2), dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Papers written after Reade's death, relating to real estate, etc. (2 of 2), dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - "The Autobiography of a Thief": notes and drafts in two stitched notebooks, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Manuscript entitled "Hear both sides" ("The bloomer") in one stitched notebook, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Christie Johnstone: AMs, one leaf, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Double Marriage: agreements, letters, etc., relating to the play, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - The Countess and the Dancer: manuscript of Acts I and III, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - "Doubles": one leaf of manuscript, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Le Faubourg St. Germaine, Act I: rough draft in one stitched notebook, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - It's never too late to mend: notes, preliminary drafts, etc., for the novel, in two stitched notebooks and loose leaves, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - It's never too late to mend: Acts 2 and 4 of drama in four stitched notebooks, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - It's never too late to mend: unauthorized production, 1863 (Reade vs. Mills), dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - It's never too late to mend: John Coleman's production, 1865-1867; portion of 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - It's never too late to mend: unauthorized production, 1867; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - It's never too late to mend: "Scene added to the last act... for Miss Ellen Terry by her friend the author", undated; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - The 'jilt': partial manuscript, undated; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - "Love me little, love me long": AMs, one leaf, undated; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Masks and Faces: changes to Act I, Scene 1, in hand of author, undated; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Masks and Faces: changes to Act I, Scene 1, in hand of an amanuensis, undated; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Masks and Faces agreements. etc., undated; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - Put yourself in his place: agreement concerning Coleman's proposed U.S. production, undated; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Reade, Charles Liston, 1844-1917; 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Reade, Compton, 1834-1909; 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - Redesdale, Algernon Bertram Freeman-Mitford, 1st Baron, 1837-1916; portion of 1 folder
    - ALS to Edmund Gosse, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Reilly, Garrett L., d. 1955, undated; 2 folders (2 partial)
    - Correspondence and other material relating to his Anthony Trollope collection (1 of 2), undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence and other material relating to his Anthony Trollope collection (2 of 2), undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Rhead, Louis, 1857-1926; portion of 1 folder
    - ALS to Miss Furman, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Richards, Aline, undated; portion of 1 folder
    - Branwell Brontë: a play in three acts, in a bound notebook, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Ritchie, Lady Anne Isabella Thackeray, 1837-1919; 5 folders (4 partial)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Letters to W. J. Williams of Smith, Elder & Co. (1 of 2), undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Letters to W. J. Williams of Smith, Elder & Co. (2 of 2), undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Letters addressed to Lady Ritchie, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - "The Life of Jane Austen," original MS andd proof, undated; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 9a)
  - Rose, Philip, Sir, 1816-1889; portion of 1 folder
    - ALS to Jonas Levy, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Sadleir, Michael, 1888-1957; portions of 2 boxes
    - Letters from Henry M. Trollope and his wife, Ada, and daughter, Muriel, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Articles, clippings and other material relating to Anthony Trollope, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Typescripts and notes concerning Anthony Trollope, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Items removed from extra-illustrated Anthony Trollope: a commentary, Boston, 1927; portion of 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Saint-Gaudens, Augustus, undated; 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous correspondence and material, undated; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 2A)
  - Sawyer, Chas. J., Ltd., London, undated; portion of 1 folder
    - Correspondence relating to the sale of the "MacGeorge Pickwick" to M. L. Parrish, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Sayers, Dorothy Leigh, 1893-1957; portion of 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Scott, Clement William, 1841-1904; portion of 1 folder
    - "Mr. Charles Reade and his Critics. To the Editor of the Era." Also includes 3 ALSs to George Robert Sims, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Scott, Walter, 1771-1832, Correspondence, 1803-1829; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 5A)
  - Seaver, William A., undated; portion of 1 folder
    - Letters to Seaver concerning Wilkie Collins, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Shorter, Clement, 1917 February 8; 1 folder
    - LS to the Rt. Hon. John Burns, London, 1917 February 8; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 6A)
  - Stanley, Arthur Penrhyn, 1815-1881; portion of 1 folder
    - Letters to Mr. and Mrs. Charles Kingsley and to Rose Kingsley, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Stapleton, Augustus Granville, undated; 1 folder
    - Correspondence and Documents, undated; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Stevenson, Fanny Van de Grift, 1840-1914; 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Stevenson, Robert, 1772-1850; 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Stevenson, Robert Louis, 1850-1894; 20 folders
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Letters to Mr. and Mrs. Thomas Stevenson (parents), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Letters to Edmund Goss, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Documents, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Catriona: draft of title page, under the title David Balfour, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - "Franklin... Dialogue concerning virtue and pleasure", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - In the South Seas: AMs, one leaf, inlaid, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - In the South Seas: chapter headings, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - The Master of Ballantrae: AMs, one leaf, mounted, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - St. Ives: title page, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - St. Ives: chapters 1-7, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - St. Ives: chapters 8-13, undated; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - St. Ives: chapters 14-18, undated; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - St. Ives: chapters 19-24, undated; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - St. Ives: chapters 25-26 and miscellaneous leaves, undated; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - "Though he that ever kind and true...": AMs of poem, undated; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - The Wrecker: portion of Chapter XX, undated; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - "The Young Chevalier" (8 lines of Stevenson's writing), undated; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Pencil drawing of a village, undated; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 29)
    - Self-portrait in academic garb, matted, undated; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 30)
  - Stevenson, Thomas, 1818-1887; 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 31)
  - Stewart, Harriet Everilda Gore, d., 1884; portion of 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Stoddard, Richard Henry, 1825-1903; portion of 1 folder
    - "Adsum": original AMsS of poem written on the occasion of the death of William Makepeace Thackeray, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Strong, Austin, 1881-1952; portion of 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Symonds, John Addington, 1840-1893; portion of 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Tauchnitz, Bernhard, Freiherr von, 1816-1895; portion of 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Taylor, Tom, 1817-1880; portion of 1 folder
    - "L'Église Buissonnière" (poem), with ANS by Thomas Hughes at the top, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Terry, Florence, undated; portion of 1 folder
    - ALS to Miss Ethel Barclay, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863; 11 folders (5 partial)
    - Letter to John Frederick Boyes, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Letter addressed to Thackeray, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Autograph Ms. notes for "The English Humorists", undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - The Virginians: one page in copyist's hand, with a few autograph corrections by Thackeray, written on the back of a ALS letter to Thackeray, undated; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Pencil and ink drawing of a clock, undated; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Color drawing for "The original Agapemone in Danger," published in Punch, undated; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Pen-and-ink drawing of a sailor, published in Punch, undated; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - "Eating his Christmas pie" drawing, undated; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Pencil and pen-and-ink sketches, undated; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Thirkell, Angela, 1956; 1 folder
    - ALS to Mr. Dix, undated; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 18A)
  - Tilley, Sir John, 1813-1898; 1 folder
    - Letter to Anthony Trollope, undated; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - Trollope, Anthony, 1734-1806; 1 folder
    - Church record, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - Trollope, Anthony, 1815-1882; portions of 3 boxes
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, not in Booth edition (1 of 3), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, not in Booth edition (2 of 3), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, not in Booth edition (3 of 3), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, not in Booth edition: photostats and transcripts, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, included in Booth edition: photostats and transcripts, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, included in Booth edition, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, not in Hall edition, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Letters to Mrs. Bronson, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Letters to Frederic Chapman, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Letters to William Isbister, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Letters to Harriet and Mary Knower, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Letters to Rose Trollope, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Letters to Rose Trollope; transcripts by Muriel R. Trollope, undated; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Letters to Thomas Adolphus Trollope, undated; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Letters addressed to Trollope, undated; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Letters addressed to Trollope; transcripts by Muriel R. Trollope, undated; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material, undated; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Bank checks, undated; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - The Life of Cicero: Ms. in the hand of Rose Trollope, with changes and additions by the author, undated; portions of 2 boxes
      - Preliminary leaves and Volume I, chapter 1, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 14)
      - Volume I, chapter 2, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 15)
      - Volume I, chapter 3, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 16)
      - Volume I, chapter 4, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 17)
      - Volume I, chapter 5, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 18)
      - Volume I, chapter 6, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 19)
      - Volume I, chapter 7, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 20)
      - Volume I, chapter 8, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 21)
      - Volume I, chapter 9, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 22)
      - Volume I, chapter 10, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 23)
      - Volume I, chapter 11, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Volume I, chapter 12, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Volume I, chapter 13 (Volume II, chapter 1), dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Volume I, Appendices, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Volume II, chapter 1 (chapter 2), dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Volume II, chapter 2 (chapter 3), dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Volume II, chapter 3 (chapter 4), dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - Volume II, chapter 4 (chapter 5), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - Volume II, chapter 5 (chapter 6), undated; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - Volume II, chapter 6 (chapter 7), undated; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - Volume II, chapter 7 (chapter 8), undated; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - Volume II, chapter 8 (chapter 9), undated; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 12)
      - Volume II, chapter 9 (chapter 10), undated; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 13)
      - Volume II, chapter 10 (chapter 11), undated; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 14)
      - Volume II, chapter 11 (chapter 12), undated; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 15)
      - Volume II, chapter 12 (chapter 13), undated; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 16)
      - Volume II, chapter 13 (chapter 12) and Appendices, undated; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Orley Farm: drawing for title on spine (originally laid in Jennings-Sadleir copy), undated; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - Travel letters, nos. 5-17 (duplicates), undated; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - Travel letter no. 20 (photostat), undated; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Trollope, Frances Eleanor Ternan, 1835-1913 (second wife of Thomas Adolphus Trollope), undated; 1 folder